PORTAL DEVELOPER

Career Overview

Engineering computer with expertise in system development, system architecture IT and currently as a project manager seeks a similar role to collaborate on the continuous growth of the company and quality attention to their users and clients.

Qualifications

- Flexibility and adaptation to change
- Proactive leadership
- Self-learning
- Team working
- Work under pressure

Work Experience

Portal Developer

October 2014 to Current Emmes i1/4 Rockville, MD

- Developing portal themes.
- Developing portlets.
- · Responsive design.
- Developing prototypes.
- Fixing issues on modules developed.
- Developing styles guide documentation.

Sr. Developer Java

April 2014 to October 2014 Freddie Mac il/4 Atlanta, GA

• Developing modules at "Grupo Modelo" system based in JEE platform (Spring, JQuery, WS).

Project Leader

December 2013 to April 2014 Intersection il/4 Seattle, WA

- Managing projects with SCRUM and PMI methodologies.
- Managing applications migrating done with Delphi to JEE technologies.
- Designing and testing new security architecture by Delphi systems.
- Developing corporative modules by new systems, like email sender.
- I collaborated in the architecture design of migrating components.

Project Leader - Project Manager Professional at Infonavit

July 2011 to October 2013 Interware i1/4 City, STATE

- Managing Infonavit portal projects with PMI methodology.
- Collecting user requirements.
- Making architecture definitions by portal components.
- Making solution alternative for each user requirement.
- Managing team assigned to portal.
- Managing project's budget.
- Designing and managing unit test, stress tests and bandwidth tests of each of portal components.
- Taking control of hours in to the project.
- Making advance of projects report.
- Managing delivery of each portal component.
- · Managing providers.
- Designing standards applied each portal component developed.
- I contributed to a 20% increase the requirements worked due to a component framework designed to promote reuse of functionality.

Project Manager Professional

March 2011 to July 2011 ICreativa i1/4 City, STATE

- Managing projects with PMI methodology.
- Collecting user requirements.
- Making solution alternative for each user requirement.
- Managing team assigned to project.
- Managing budget of project.
- Designing and managing unit tests, stress tests and bandwidth tests of each components.
- Managing delivery of each component.
- I finished the project in a short time by reutilization code implemented.

WebSites Subdirector

November 2008 to February 2011 Mexican Government - SecretarÃa De La FunciÃ3n Pública i¼ City, STATE

- Managing projects with PMI and RUP methodologies.
- Collecting user requirements.
- Making solution alternative for each user requirement.
- Managing team assigned to JEE development.
- Making the final architecture used by new developments.
- Managing providers.
- Managing project leaders.
- I reduced development time by components reutilization and I increased the projects attended than last year.

México, D.F. Leader Developer

October 2005 to October 2008 Mexican Government - Aeropuertos Y Servicios Auxiliares il/4 City, STATE

- Developing portal applications.
- Migrating of different applications made in PHP to Java technologies.
- Managing projects with PMI and RUP methodologies.
- Managing providers.
- I increased update time in portal content actualization process.
- I deleted INFOTEC consulters by WebBuilder tool due my analysis and attention that I offered in order to develop user requirements.

Jr. Programmer

October 2004 to October 2005 Accenture Technology Solutions México, D.F i1/4 City, STATE

• Developing interfaces between automatic provisioning and Telmex network inventory.

Jr. Programmer

May 2002 to October 2004 Impulsora De Ventas Internacional México, D.F i¼ City, STATE

- Developing applications with technologies PHP, Java, Linux, MySQL.
- Managing company servers.
- Collecting and developing systems by user requirements.

Trainee

November 2001 to May 2002 UNAM DGSCA - AdministraciÃ³n De Servidores i¹/₄ City, STATE

- Supporting different management server activities.
- Developing applications with PHP and Java languages.

México, D.F. Telephonic Operator

August 2001 to May 2002 SITEL $i\frac{1}{4}$ City, STATE

• Configuring Internet by dial-up.

Education and Training

BA: Computer Engineering, 2001 UNAM - FES i1/4 City, State, México

Computer Engineering

Project Management Professional (PMP4), 06/13/2011. SAP Certified Development Associate- ABAP with SAP Net Weaver 7.0, 04/18/2013 IBM Certified System Administrator - WebSphere Portal 7.0, 09/21/2012 IBM Certified Solution Developer - WebSphere Portal 7.0, 06/01/2012 Oracle Certified Master, Java SE 6 Developer, 04/12/2012. Sun Certified Java Programmer, Standard Edition 5.0, 10/24/2007. Zend Certified Engineer (Zend PHP 5 Certification), 05/18/2007.

Skills

ABAP, Apache, Architect, budget, C, C++, content, Content Management, Crystal Reports, CVS, Databases, delivery, Delphi, Designing, documentation, Eclipse, email, Engineer, English, EJB, HTML, IBM, IBM WebSphere, WebSphere, IDE, inventory, ITIL, Java, Beans, JavaScript, JBoss, Languages, leadership, Linux, Macromedia Suite, Managing, MS-Excel, Office, Power Point, MS-Project, Windows, MS-Word, MySQL, Enterprise, network, Oracle, Developer, PL/SQL, PHP 5, PHP, Programmer, Project Leader, Project Management, RAD, Reporting, requirement, RUP, SAP, SDLC, servers, Shell, SQL Server, Struts, Sun, Sybase, System Administrator, Tomcat, UML, Unix, Websites, Weblogic, XML